<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Draft on Research Agent Knowledge Base</title>
    <link>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/tags/draft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Draft on Research Agent Knowledge Base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ko-kr</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/tags/draft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Can AI Generate more Comprehensive Test Scenarios? Review on Automated Driving Systems Test Scenario Generation Methods</title>
      <link>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/can-ai-generate-more-comprehensive-test-scenarios-review-on-automated-driving-systems-test-scenario-generation-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/can-ai-generate-more-comprehensive-test-scenarios-review-on-automated-driving-systems-test-scenario-generation-methods/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Ensuring the safety and reliability of Automated Driving Systems (ADS) remains a critical challenge, as traditional verification methods such as large-scale on-road testing are prohibitively costly and time-consuming.To address this,scenario-based testing has emerged as a scalable and efficient alternative,yet existing surveys provide only partial coverage of recent methodological and technological advances.This review systematically analyzes 31 primary studies,and 10 surveys identified through a comprehensive search spanning 2015~2025;however,the in-depth methodological synthesis and comparative evaluation focus primarily on recent frameworks(2023~2025),reflecting the surge of Artificial Intelligent(AI)-assisted and multimodal approaches in this period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exciton radiative lifetimes in hexagonal diamond Ge and Si$_x$Ge$_{1-x}$ alloys</title>
      <link>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/exciton-radiative-lifetimes-in-hexagonal-diamond-ge-and-sixge1-x-alloys/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/exciton-radiative-lifetimes-in-hexagonal-diamond-ge-and-sixge1-x-alloys/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Recent reports of strong room-temperature photoluminescence in hexagonal diamond (2H) germanium stand in marked contrast to theoretical predictions of very weak band-edge optical transitions. Here we address radiative emission in 2H-Ge and related materials through a comprehensive investigation of their excitonic properties and radiative lifetimes, performing Bethe-Salpeter calculations on pristine and uniaxially strained 2H-Ge, 2H-Si$x$Ge${1-x}$ alloys with $x=\frac{1}{6},,\frac{1}{4},,\frac{1}{2}$, and wurtzite GaN as a reference. Pristine 2H-Ge features sizable exciton binding energies ($\sim!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of (In,Ga)N pseudo-substrates by a three-step growth protocol without ex-situ processing</title>
      <link>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/fabrication-of-ingan-pseudo-substrates-by-a-three-step-growth-protocol-without-ex-situ-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/fabrication-of-ingan-pseudo-substrates-by-a-three-step-growth-protocol-without-ex-situ-processing/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We fabricate (In,Ga)N pseudo-substrates with a total thickness of ~1 um grown on GaN templates using plasma-assisted molecular beam epitaxy. In a three-step process, we change growth conditions from N-rich to metal-rich in order to sequentially form a roughened GaN layer, relaxed (In,Ga)N nanostructures, and a coalesced, smooth (In,Ga)N layer. Samples are analyzed by scanning electron and atomic force microscopy, X-ray diffraction, as well as photo- and cathodoluminescence spectroscopy. Compared to a reference layer grown directly on GaN, the pseudo-substrate exhibits a higher In content (~0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MeltwaterBench: Deep learning for spatiotemporal downscaling of surface meltwater</title>
      <link>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/meltwaterbench-deep-learning-for-spatiotemporal-downscaling-of-surface-meltwater/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/meltwaterbench-deep-learning-for-spatiotemporal-downscaling-of-surface-meltwater/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The Greenland ice sheet is melting at an accelerated rate due to processes that are not fully understood and hard to measure. The distribution of surface meltwater can help understand these processes and is observable through remote sensing, but current maps of meltwater face a trade-off: They are either high-resolution in time or space, but not both. We develop a deep learning model that creates gridded surface meltwater maps at daily 100m resolution by fusing data streams from remote sensing observations and physics-based models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated Rotation-Invariant Convolution for UAV Image Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/accelerated-rotation-invariant-convolution-for-uav-image-segmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/accelerated-rotation-invariant-convolution-for-uav-image-segmentation/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Rotation invariance is essential for precise, object-level segmentation in UAV aerial imagery, where targets can have arbitrary orientations and exhibit fine-scale details. Conventional segmentation architectures like U-Net rely on convolution operators that are not rotation-invariant, leading to degraded segmentation accuracy across varying viewpoints. Rotation invariance can be achieved by expanding the filter bank across multiple orientations; however, this will significantly increase computational cost and memory traffic. In this paper, we introduce a GPU-optimized rotation-invariant convolution framework that eliminates the traditional data-lowering (im2col) step required for matrix-multiplication-based convolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clinical Interpretability of Deep Learning Segmentation Through Shapley-Derived Agreement and Uncertainty Metrics</title>
      <link>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/clinical-interpretability-of-deep-learning-segmentation-through-shapley-derived-agreement-and-uncertainty-metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/clinical-interpretability-of-deep-learning-segmentation-through-shapley-derived-agreement-and-uncertainty-metrics/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Segmentation is the identification of anatomical regions of interest, such as organs, tissue, and lesions, serving as a fundamental task in computer-aided diagnosis in medical imaging. Although deep learning models have achieved remarkable performance in medical image segmentation, the need for explainability remains critical for ensuring their acceptance and integration in clinical practice, despite the growing research attention in this area. Our approach explored the use of contrast-level Shapley values, a systematic perturbation of model inputs to assess feature importance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robust Variational Model Based Tailored UNet: Leveraging Edge Detector and Mean Curvature for Improved Image Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/robust-variational-model-based-tailored-unet-leveraging-edge-detector-and-mean-curvature-for-improved-image-segmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/robust-variational-model-based-tailored-unet-leveraging-edge-detector-and-mean-curvature-for-improved-image-segmentation/</guid>
      <description>Abstract To address the challenge of segmenting noisy images with blurred or fragmented boundaries, this paper presents a robust version of Variational Model Based Tailored UNet (VM_TUNet), a hybrid framework that integrates variational methods with deep learning. The proposed approach incorporates physical priors, an edge detector and a mean curvature term, into a modified Cahn-Hilliard equation, aiming to combine the interpretability and boundary-smoothing advantages of variational partial differential equations (PDEs) with the strong representational ability of deep neural networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAUNet: A Lightweight UNet Variant with Deformable Convolutions and Parameter-Free Attention for Medical Image Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/daunet-a-lightweight-unet-variant-with-deformable-convolutions-and-parameter-free-attention-for-medical-image-segmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/daunet-a-lightweight-unet-variant-with-deformable-convolutions-and-parameter-free-attention-for-medical-image-segmentation/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Medical image segmentation plays a pivotal role in automated diagnostic and treatment planning systems. In this work, we present DAUNet, a novel lightweight UNet variant that integrates Deformable V2 Convolutions and Parameter-Free Attention (SimAM) to improve spatial adaptability and context-aware feature fusion without increasing model complexity. DAUNet&amp;rsquo;s bottleneck employs dynamic deformable kernels to handle geometric variations, while the decoder and skip pathways are enhanced using SimAM attention modules for saliency-aware refinement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lean Unet: A Compact Model for Image Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/lean-unet-a-compact-model-for-image-segmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/lean-unet-a-compact-model-for-image-segmentation/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Unet and its variations have been standard in semantic image segmentation, especially for computer assisted radiology. Current Unet architectures iteratively downsample spatial resolution while increasing channel dimensions to preserve information content. Such a structure demands a large memory footprint, limiting training batch sizes and increasing inference latency. Channel pruning compresses Unet architecture without accuracy loss, but requires lengthy optimization and may not generalize across tasks and datasets. By investigating Unet pruning, we hypothesize that the final structure is the crucial factor, not the channel selection strategy of pruning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Discrete Neural Operator with Adaptive Sampling for Surrogate Modeling of Parametric Transient Darcy Flows in Porous Media</title>
      <link>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/a-discrete-neural-operator-with-adaptive-sampling-for-surrogate-modeling-of-parametric-transient-darcy-flows-in-porous-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/a-discrete-neural-operator-with-adaptive-sampling-for-surrogate-modeling-of-parametric-transient-darcy-flows-in-porous-media/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This study proposes a new discrete neural operator for surrogate modeling of transient Darcy flow fields in heterogeneous porous media with random parameters. The new method integrates temporal encoding, operator learning and UNet to approximate the mapping between vector spaces of random parameter and spatiotemporal flow fields. The new discrete neural operator can achieve higher prediction accuracy than the SOTA attention-residual-UNet structure. Derived from the finite volume method, the transmissibility matrices rather than permeability is adopted as the inputs of surrogates to enhance the prediction accuracy further.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multifractal Recalibration of Neural Networks for Medical Imaging Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/multifractal-recalibration-of-neural-networks-for-medical-imaging-segmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/multifractal-recalibration-of-neural-networks-for-medical-imaging-segmentation/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Multifractal analysis has revealed regularities in many self-seeding phenomena, yet its use in modern deep learning remains limited. Existing end-to-end multifractal methods rely on heavy pooling or strong feature-space decimation, which constrain tasks such as semantic segmentation. Motivated by these limitations, we introduce two inductive priors: Monofractal and Multifractal Recalibration. These methods leverage relationships between the probability mass of the exponents and the multifractal spectrum to form statistical descriptions of encoder embeddings, implemented as channel-attention functions in convolutional networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatiotemporal Satellite Image Downscaling with Transfer Encoders and Autoregressive Generative Models</title>
      <link>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/spatiotemporal-satellite-image-downscaling-with-transfer-encoders-and-autoregressive-generative-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/spatiotemporal-satellite-image-downscaling-with-transfer-encoders-and-autoregressive-generative-models/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We present a transfer-learning generative downscaling framework to reconstruct fine resolution satellite images from coarse scale inputs. Our approach combines a lightweight U-Net transfer encoder with a diffusion-based generative model. The simpler U-Net is first pretrained on a long time series of coarse resolution data to learn spatiotemporal representations; its encoder is then frozen and transferred to a larger downscaling model as physically meaningful latent features. Our application uses NASA&amp;rsquo;s MERRA-2 reanalysis as the low resolution source domain (50 km) and the GEOS-5 Nature Run (G5NR) as the high resolution target (7 km).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Satellite to Street : Disaster Impact Estimator</title>
      <link>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/satellite-to-street-disaster-impact-estimator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/satellite-to-street-disaster-impact-estimator/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Accurate post-disaster damage assessment is of high importance for prioritizing emergency response; however, manual interpretation of satellite imagery is slow, subjective, and hard to scale. While deep-learning models for image segmentation, such as U-Net-based baselines and change-detection models, are useful baselines, they often struggle with subtle structural variations and severe class imbalance, yielding poor detection of highly damaged regions. The present work proposes a deep-learning framework that jointly processes pre- and post-disaster satellite images to obtain fine-grained pixel-level damage maps: Satellite-to-Street: Disaster Impact Estimator.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
