<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Deep learning on Research Agent Knowledge Base</title>
    <link>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/tags/deep-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Deep learning on Research Agent Knowledge Base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ko-kr</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/tags/deep-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MeltwaterBench: Deep learning for spatiotemporal downscaling of surface meltwater</title>
      <link>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/meltwaterbench-deep-learning-for-spatiotemporal-downscaling-of-surface-meltwater/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/meltwaterbench-deep-learning-for-spatiotemporal-downscaling-of-surface-meltwater/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The Greenland ice sheet is melting at an accelerated rate due to processes that are not fully understood and hard to measure. The distribution of surface meltwater can help understand these processes and is observable through remote sensing, but current maps of meltwater face a trade-off: They are either high-resolution in time or space, but not both. We develop a deep learning model that creates gridded surface meltwater maps at daily 100m resolution by fusing data streams from remote sensing observations and physics-based models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clinical Interpretability of Deep Learning Segmentation Through Shapley-Derived Agreement and Uncertainty Metrics</title>
      <link>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/clinical-interpretability-of-deep-learning-segmentation-through-shapley-derived-agreement-and-uncertainty-metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hanwo-ol.github.io/Unet_master/posts/clinical-interpretability-of-deep-learning-segmentation-through-shapley-derived-agreement-and-uncertainty-metrics/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Segmentation is the identification of anatomical regions of interest, such as organs, tissue, and lesions, serving as a fundamental task in computer-aided diagnosis in medical imaging. Although deep learning models have achieved remarkable performance in medical image segmentation, the need for explainability remains critical for ensuring their acceptance and integration in clinical practice, despite the growing research attention in this area. Our approach explored the use of contrast-level Shapley values, a systematic perturbation of model inputs to assess feature importance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
